Guide to the Henry Guerlac papers, 1922-1981
Guerlac, Henry papers, 1922-1981
- Series VI: History of Science Society
  - Libraries and collections of the history of science (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Libraries of science and technology (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Burndy Library (Bern Dibner) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - History of science elsewhere (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - St. John's (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence on history of science courses (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous organizations (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Material for revision of bibliography (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 17th century bibliography additions (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Form sheet for bibliography (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Outline of bibliography (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 15-16)
  - Bibliographies (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Science Reference Sources (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Bibliography of American Fundamental Scientific Research (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - History of Science Essay Prize (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Cohen--The Principles of Physical Science at Harvard (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Cohen (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Report to American Council of Learned Societies on Isis (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Project for Continuing the Sarton Introduction (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Ross Harrison--Advertising (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Mrs. Strelsky-- Isis (confidential) (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Committee on the History of Science and General Education--History of Science Society (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Humanistic Aspects--David Hawkins (Box 7, Folder 29-30)
- Series VII: History of Science materials
  - History of Science Society, 1950s (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - History of Science Society - general, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - History of Science Society, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - History of Science Society, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - History of Science Society, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Finance Committee--Social Report (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Richmond--the History and Method of Science at Williams (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Princeton Symposium on Measurement of Technological Change, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Harvard Summer School--Special Session, July 1951 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Schryock Project (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - 11th International Congress--Poland (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Académie Internationale d'Historie des Sciences (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - History of Science Congress, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - History of Science/Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Soviet/American Conference, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 45-46)
  - Scientific autographs (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - John Fulton (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Haskins, Charles Homer (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Koyre, Alexander (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Mieli, Aldo (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Neugebauer, Otto (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Prof. J.R. Partington (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Henry Sigerist (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Singer, Charles and Dorothea Waley (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Sudhoff, Karl (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Paul Tannery (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Temkin, Owsei (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Thorndike, Lynn (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Definitions of physics (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Acta Eruditorum; Leibniz' review of Clarke's Rouhault, Oct. 1713 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Acta Eruditorum, Review of Optics, Feb. 1706 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Abacus, arabic numeral, and exchequer (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Al-Biruni on India (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Albertus Magnus (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Archimedes (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Aristotle (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - D. Bernoulli (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Cardan, Jerome (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Coleridge (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Marvin on Comte and Sarton (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Copernicus 8 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Crevecoeur (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Theron Cole on Dalton (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - M. Daumas, L'elaboration du Traite de Chimie de Lavoisier (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - John Dee (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - G.B. Dellaporta (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - J.A. DeLuc (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - DeLuc on thermometry (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Pierre Prevost and the Swiss (Genevan) School (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Digges's "Perfect Description" (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - J. Duboul: "Dortous de Mairan" (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - The Newtonianism of Dortous de Mairan (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Rene Dubos: "Science and Man's Nature" (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - General Duportail (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Duportail (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Fourcray: "Leçons elémentaires" (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Galen (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Galileo - Dialogues (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Galileo (Box 8, Folder 18-19)
  - Geoffroy to Sloane (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Geoffroy's summary of Optice or Opticks, 1906-1907 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Gesner, Conrad (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - B. Silliman: "Journal of Travels in England" (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Stukeley (and Hales) (Box 8, Folder 24-26)
  - Fixed Air and Hales (Box 8, Folder 27-28)
  - Stephen Hales - D.N.B. article (Box 8, Folder 29-30)
  - du Clos: Observations sur le vin (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - J.B. du Hamel on Calcination (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Harvey, William (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Huxley on Darwin's Origin of Species (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Brownie Kennedy on Providence (Box 8, Folder 35-36)
  - Kinetic theory--Bibliography (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Kinetic theory--Hawkins on Vis Viva (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Theories of heat (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Loval: Voyage à la Louisiane (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Louville, Chevalier de (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Leonardo da Vinci (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Lexell and Academy of Science (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Marin Marais (from John Hsu) (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - McClurg: De Calore (Box 8, Folder 45-46)
  - Lettre à Monsieur de Marivets (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Masonry (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Mayow Studies--revisions and additions (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Guyton de Morveau--biographies (Box 8, Folder 50-51)
  - Pascal (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Priestly, Joseph (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Privat de Molieres (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Ptolemy (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Sage Article (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Gilbert and Charles Romme - Stroganoff (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Tartaglia (Box 8, Folder 58-59)
  - Van Helmont (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Translation of Vavilov (Box 8, Folder 61-62)
  - Vesalius (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Villard d'Honecourt (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Voltaire (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Rabelais at Montpellier (Box 8, Folder 66-67)
- Series VIII: Early drafts and articles
  - Joseph Black on heat (carbon copies) (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Medieval intellectual history (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - University of Colorado? Science lectures (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Bibliography outline (mimeo) (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - University of Michigan (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Iowa State - Case Institute of Tech, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Clare Hall, Cambridge, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Toronto, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Dictionary of Scientific Biography - Lavoisier (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Dictionary of Scientific Biography Reviews (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Dictionary of Scientific Biography article--Comments of critics (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Guy de La Brosse--Sources (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - La Brosse - Botanical gardens (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - La Brosse - Bibliography (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - La Brosse, Correspondence about (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - La Brosse - Botany at Montpellier (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - La Brosse--Herouard and Riviere (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - La Brosse--Paracelsian and Montpellier Men (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - La Brosse--Sharrock on plant nutrition (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - La Brosse-- Dictionary of Scientific Biography article (draft) (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Guy de La Brosse and air in plants (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - La Brosse-- De la Nature, vertu, et utilité des plantes (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - La Brosse--Notes (1st draft (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - La Brosse--Pagel Festschrift (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - French Paracelsian Tradition (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Early papers and articles--Guide copy (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Series IX: Comets
  - Comets--Eclipse of 1715 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Comets--Pamphlets on comets (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Comets and Copernicus (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Comets--Chiarmonti, Scipione on Comets (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Foscarini on Gravity (1661) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Comets (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Descartes on comets (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Hooke on comets (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Translation of Herz on comets (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Borelli (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Borelli (Mutoli) (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Seth Ward (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Gases (Box 9, Folder 18-19)
  - Cassini on comet of 1664 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Delambre on comets (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Horrox on comets (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Kepler on comets (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Pierre Petit--Dissertation (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Comet paths (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Comet of 1664 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Notes from Birch on comet of 1664 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Comet of 1664--Outline of paper (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Manilius on comets (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Carnot's cycle (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Masao Watanabe: The Development of the Dynamic Theory of Heat in Early Nineteenth Century England (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Secondary sources on kinetic theory and mechanical theory of heat (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Jaroansky on dialectical materialism and science (Box 9, Folder 33)
- Series X: Books, papers, drafts
  - Pardies on comets (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Hevelius (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Edward Sherburne--Sphere of Manilius (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Pardies: De motu et natura cometarum (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Robert M. McKeon on Auzout (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - G. Atkinsin: "Precurseurs le Boyle et de Fontenelle" (Comet of 1664-1665) (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Seneca on comets (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Phil. Trans. (1665) on comet of 1664-1665 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Early observations of comets (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Loletschek - Comets of 1664, 1665 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Norbert Herz on comet paths (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Doris Hellman on Tycho, etc. (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Review of Oldenburg correspondence (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Dictionary of Scientific Biography--Lavoisier (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Lavoisier (Box 9, Folder 48-53)
  - Radar in World War II--Holton (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Lavoisier--Laplace (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - A History of Radar, Part I: "The Background of Radio Detection" (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - A History of Radar, Part II: "Longer Wave Radar" (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - A History of Radar, Part III: The Origins of Microwave Radar (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Chapter V, Radar Research by the Signal Corps (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Newton in France (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Newton in France (Box 10, Folder 1-5)
  - Radar--Dubridge Symposium, "The War Years," Dale R. Corson, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - "Early Development of Science," An Essay, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "Report on the History of Science," (Master Copy), 1950 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - "The Development of Modern Science," by Ernest Nagel, Chap. 7, in Chapters in Western Civilization (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - George Sarton and the Positivist Tradition in the History of Science, Tore Frangsmyr (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - The Johns Hopkins University Press (Box 10, Folder 11-13)
  - Dictionary of Scientific Biography--Vauban (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
  - Copyrights (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - The Ronald Press Company (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Filing, OV (correspondence), 1973-1975 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Contracts (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Permissions: Collected works and essays (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Hull bequest (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Makers of modern strategy (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Felix Gilbert (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - The state of the history of science (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Encyclopedia Americana (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Yale, July 1975 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Knopf (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Russell McCormick--H.G. Reprints (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Little, Brown and Company (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Scottish Enlightenment (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Ira Wade, Festschrift, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Newton book--J.H. Plumb (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Book on Lavoisier (Scribners) (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Permissions (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence re: Lavoisier Book (Scribners) (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Newton on the Continent (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Cornell Press (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - "The Early Development of Science," an essay (Box 10, Folder 38)
- Series XI: Lectures, papers, reviews
  - Departmental business - Wisconsin, 1941-1942 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence concerning students - Wisconsin (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Wartime clippings (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Radio talk on Bach at Wisconsin (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Presbyterian Couples Club, Apr. 1942 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - "Benjamin Franklin à Paris," French Club, University of Wisconsin, Mar. 25, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Address to Wisconsin Engineer Banquet, Mar. 1942 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - "Science and War in the Renaissance," Baker Lab., June, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - 4. "Science under the Terror" (Version II of paper read at Chicago in 1941 ), Research Club Paper, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Schweitzer and 18th Century Humanism (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Talk to Chemists' Colloquium, Spring, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Arab and Byzantium science--Special lecture (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - "War and the French Revolution" (Daniels' seminar) (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Radio series--"What's New in Science?" (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Harvard Conference on History of Science, July, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Theory of the pseudo-sciences given to Vicious Circle and graduate students, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Speech at Gettysburg, Pa., Feb. 6, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - "Science and French National Strength," Princeton, Feb. 4, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - "The Reflection of some 18th Century Scientific Ideas in Montesquieu's ..." Brown University, Dec. 6, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Was early medicine a pseudo-science? (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - History of science elsewhere (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Philosophy 2, Henry E. Guerlac (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Tape of Dartmouth lecture (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Personnel in History of Science (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - History of Science Society, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Finished articles (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Stimson Lecture at Goucher (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - "Early Navigation Technics," Ithaca Rotary, Mar. 3, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Vicious Circle (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Radio talk on science books (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Wisconsin Symposium remarks, Jan. 1949 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - "Atomic Energy", Trumansburg PTA, Jan. 1949 (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - Development of the altimeter (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - Review: Conant's Understanding Science ( Scripta Mathematica) (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - The early history of microwaves (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - Review: Huxley's Man Stands Alone (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - Review: Jone's "Medicine and Philosophy in Ancient Greece" ( The Philosophical Review) (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - "The Engineer and the Scientist, The Cornell Engineer, Mar. 1947 (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - "Our Relations with France"--Radio (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - "Scientists and Society," Jan. 1942, University of Chicago Sociologists Research Club (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - "The Scientist and History," Cornell Review, Sept. 1950 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - First drafts of the Development and Future Prospects of the History of Science (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - "Radio Background of Radar,", May 1949 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - "History and the Sciences", American Association for the Advancement of Science, Dec. 1947 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Paper on 18th C. for Abrams (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - General 18th C. lecture for E. Fox, Jan. 1950 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - "The Invention of Radar" (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Scientific research in government service (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Plates (photos) on Donnecourt for readings (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Wells College, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Vassar Symposium (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Science as Uncommon Sense, Sweetbriar College, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Toronto Meeting (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Travel--University of Miami (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Travel--University of Wisconsin, Apr. 7, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Travel Reimbursement (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Smith College, Mar. 1971 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Symposium on Science and Culture, University of Vermont, Mar. 30, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Travel--Pittsburgh, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Society for French Historical Studies, Mar. 29-30, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Travel--McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Stahl Memorial Lecture (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - American Societies for 18 Century Studies (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Univ. of Western Ontario, 27-28 Sept., 1976 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology: Northeastern American Society for Eighteenth Century Studies Conference, Oct. 1981 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Reed College (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Berkeley Lecture, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Conference on Biochemistry, May 31-June 2,1978 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - The Growth of Modern Science (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Glass Making in the Middle Ages (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - "What Shall We Do with Science?", Fall, Harvard Dental Alumni Association, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Harvard--Horblit Lecture, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Rutgers--History of Science, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Defense of the History of Science (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Orientation lecture--Freshman engineers (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Lecture: "Science During the First Years of the Republic: 1783-1800" (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Vicious Circle--Meeting and paper (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Age of Enlightenment--History 444, Spring, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Libri and Chasles--Book and Bowl, May 18, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Referee for article (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Photographs--Award (Box 11, Folder 38)
- Series XII: Correspondence file: Cornell students and colleagues, A-Z
  - Henry Guerlac's Graduate Students (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Phyllis Allen Richmond (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Alpert, Harry (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Sigmund Beale (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Guy Beaujouan (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Marie Boas (Box 11, Folder 44-47)
  - Carl Boyer (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Burlingame, Leslie (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Clagett, Marshall (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Corson, David (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - Curti, Merle (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - Daumas, Maurice (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Dibner, Bern (Box 11, Folder 54)
  - Dobbs, Betty (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - Damon Douglas (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - Drabkin, I.E. (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Drake, Stillman (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - DuShane, Graham (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - Denis I. Duveen (Box 11, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence with Duveen (Box 11, Folder 61-62)
  - George Foote (Box 11, Folder 63)
  - Gillispie, Charles (Box 11, Folder 64)
  - Jerry Gough (Box 11, Folder 65)
  - Graduate Students--General (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - Roger Hahn (Box 11, Folder 67-69)
  - Hall, Rupert (Box 11, Folder 70)
  - Hankins, Thomas (Box 11, Folder 71)
  - Hanson, Dean C.A. (Dean of the University Faculty) (Box 11, Folder 72)
  - Harper, Michael (Harper & Brothers, publishers) (Box 11, Folder 73)
  - Hawkins, David (Box 11, Folder 74)
  - Brooke Hindle (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - Larry Holmes (HSS Committee) (Box 11, Folder 76)
  - Rio Howard (Box 11, Folder 77-79)
  - Margaret Candee Jacob (Box 11, Folder 80)
  - Juliard, Pierre (Box 11, Folder 81)
  - Kargon, Robert (Box 11, Folder 82-83)
  - Knopf, Alfred A. (Box 11, Folder 84)
  - William J. King (Box 11, Folder 85)
  - Koyre (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - Kubrin, David (Box 11, Folder 87-88)
  - Tom Kuhn (Box 11, Folder 89)
  - Joseph Lalumia (Box 11, Folder 90)
  - Langer, William (autobiography) (Box 11, Folder 91-92)
  - Leonard Marsak (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Gloria McConnaughey (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - McKinney, Lewis (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
  - Genevieve Miller (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Mollela (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Mommsen, Ted (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Leicester, Henry (Editor, Chymia) (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Magoun, H.W. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - McConnell, John W. (Dean of Graduate School) (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Everett Mendelsohn (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Karl Morrison (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Mrs. Nelkin, Dorothy (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Oppenheimer, Jane (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Jerome Ozer--A.M. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Pace, Julian (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Pelseneer, Jean (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Pepper, Mrs. Morton (Doris Hellman) (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Carleton Perrin (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Helena Pycior (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Rappaport, Rhoda (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Rockwood, Raymond O. (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Gretchen Sachse (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Nina Sandberg (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Santillana--History of Science (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Sarton, George (Box 12, Folder 26-29)
  - Sartoniana and Forward (Box 12, Folder 30-31)
  - Schneider, Homer (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Shryock, Richard (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Smokin, Fred (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Staum, Martin (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Steinhart, Victor (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Stimson, Dorothy (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Strelsky, Katharine (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Toulmin, Stephen (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Sessions, Vivian (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Settle, Thomas (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Tobey, Ronald (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Troupe, Edward Warren (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Whetstone, J. Rodney (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Woolf, Harry (Box 12, Folder 45-47)
  - Williams, L.P. (Box 12, Folder 48-49)
  - Various publishers (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Weyer, Dr. Elliot R. (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - Zirkle, Conway (Box 12, Folder 52)
- Series XIII: Journal of the History of Ideas
  - History of Ideas, 1961-1970 (Box 12, Folder 53)
  - History of Ideas, 1971-1975 (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - History of Ideas (Box 12, Folder 55, 56)
  - History of Ideas, 1976-1978 (Box 12, Folder 57)
  - History of Ideas, 1984-1985 (Box 12, Folder 58)
  - History of Ideas, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 59)
- Series XIV: Student offprints
  - Student offprints (Box 12, Folder 61-63)
- Series XV: Correspondence, 1965-1984
  - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 64)
  - Essays and Papers - Corres. re. (Box 12, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 66)
  - American Society for Eighteenth Century Studies, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
  - Amicus Plato (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Sarton Lecture, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Lindberg Project on Scientific Revolution, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - "Newton's Mathematical Way" (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Fondazione Einaudi (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - American Philosophical Society proposal, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Series XVI: Correspondence, A-Z
  - Correspondence, A-C (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, D-F (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, G (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, H (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, I, J (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, K, M (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Mc (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, N-P (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, R (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Renaissance translations (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Rappaport (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, S (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, T-Z (Box 13, Folder 25)
- Series XVII: Lecture notes: Survey course in the history of science
  - The Writing of Research Papers (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Hist. 70, Lectures 1-14 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - 8a - Minoan Script (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Syllabus Hist. 165-166 Master Copy #3 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - 1. Introductory Material (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Lectures (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - 2. The Pre-History of Western Culture (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Hist. 311 (Box 13, Folder 33)